(
"ai_sub_version": "3.5.1",
"generated_at": "2026-07-26T17:49:25.217295",
"lyrics_prompt_version": 9,
"subtitles_prompt_version": 18,
"complete": true,
"max_retries_exceeded": false,
"any_pending": false,
"settings": (
"ai": (
"model": null,
"model_subtitles": "google-gla:gemini-3.5-flash-lite",
"model_lyrics": "google-gla:gemini-3.1-flash-lite",
"rpm": 4,
"tpm": 250000,
"google": (
"file_cache_ttl": 10,
"use_files_api": true,
"max_storage_gb": 18.0
),
"search": (
"qps": 0.3,
"max_length": 4096,
"web_search_tool": "langsearch",
"timeout": 60.0,
"retries": 3,
"min_wait_seconds": 1.0,
"max_wait_seconds": 10.0,
"multiplier": 2.0
),
"validation_buffer_ms": 2000,
"verification_gap_seconds": 60,
"gap_verification_retries": 1,
"gap_verification_ignore_start": true,
"gap_verification_ignore_end": true
),
"split": (
"max_seconds": 300,
"re_encode": (
"enabled": false,
"fps": 1.0,
"height": 360,
"bitrate_kb": 35,
"threshold_mb": 20,
"duration_tolerance_ms": 100,
"encoder": null
),
"start_offset_min": 0
"thread": (
"uploads": 4,
"re_encode": 2,
"lyrics": 4,
"subtitles": 4
),
"retry": (
"per_run": 5,
"max_runs": 3,
"multiplier": 2.0,
"min_wait_seconds": 30.0,
"max_wait_seconds": 300
),
"log": (
"level": "info",
"timestamps": true,
"scrub": false,
"progress_bars": true,
"progress_bar_width": 80,
"progress_bar_refresh_seconds": 1.0
)
目覚めていく 描いた未来図
Awakening, the future map I drew,
繋ぎ合わせた パズルピース
Piecing together the puzzle pieces.
譲れない想いを胸に
With unwavering feelings in my heart,
駆け抜けてゆくよ 今すぐ
I'll run through right now.
IQ 進め progress!
IQ, advance progress!
声を合わせて さあ行こう
Voices together, now let's go!
迷いながらも 選んだ道は
Even while hesitating, the path I chose
間違ってないって 信じてる
I believe it wasn't wrong.
涙のあとに 射す光は
The light shining after the tears
いつもより少し 温かくて
Is a bit warmer than usual.
IQ 高めて progress!
IQ, raising it, progress!
限界なんて 超えてみせる
I'll show you I can surpass my limits!
響かせよう 私の歌を
Let my song resound
遥かなる空へ 届け
Reach out to the distant sky!
どんなに遠く 離れていたって
No matter how far apart we are,
心はいつも 繋がってるから
Our hearts are always connected,
だから恐れずに 踏み出せるよ
So I can step forward without fear.
君と一緒なら どこまでも
If I'm with you, anywhere!
IQ 進め progress!
IQ, advance progress!
描いた夢を 現実に変えて
Turn the dream I drew into reality!
一人じゃないから 強くなれる
I can be strong because I'm not alone.
光る未来へ さあ行こう
Toward the shining future, now let's go!
IQ PROGRESS!
どんな夢を見に行こうか
What kind of dream shall we go see?
正しさばかりに恐れ慄かないで
Don't tremble in fear just of being right
自由自在に飛び回って
Fly around freely and effortlessly
ステップ・バイ・ステップと刻んで
Carving it out step by step,
果てのないパーティを続けようか
Shall we continue the endless party?
この時代に飛び乗って
Jump into this era,
今夜この街を飛び立って
Fly out of this town tonight,
大空を飛び回って
Flying around the vast sky.
命揺らせ 命揺らせ
Shake your life, shake your life!
この風に飛び乗って
Jump on this wind,
今夜タイフーンの目となって
Be the eye of the typhoon tonight,
大空を飛び回って
Flying around the vast sky.
命揺らせ 命揺らせ
Shake your life, shake your life!
代わり映えしない日常の片隅で
In a corner of an unchanging daily life,
無邪気に笑っていられたらいいよな
I wish I could laugh innocently...
無意味な旅を続けようか
Shall we continue this meaningless journey?
ワン・バイ・ワン 一歩ずつでいさ
One by one, just one step at a time,
歓声も罵声も呑み込んで
Swallowing cheers and jeers alike.
この時代に飛び乗って
Jump into this era,
今夜愚か者喰いとなって
Becoming a fool-eater tonight,
過ちを恐れないで
Don't fear mistakes,
命揺らせ 命揺らせ
Shake your life, shake your life!
この風に飛び乗って
Jump on this wind,
今夜名もなき風となって
Becoming a nameless wind tonight,
清濁を併せ呑んで
Drinking purity and turbidity,
命揺らせ 命揺らせ
Shake your life, shake your life!
大雨降らせ
Pour down heavy rain,
大地震わせ
Make the earth shake,
過去を祝え
Celebrate the past,
明日を担え
Take on tomorrow!
命揺らせ 命揺らせ
Shake your life, shake your life!
大雨降らせ
Pour down heavy rain,
大地震わせ
Make the earth shake,
過去を祝え
Celebrate the past,
明日を担え
Take on tomorrow!
命揺らせ 命揺らせ
Shake your life, shake your life!
大雨降らせ
Pour down heavy rain,
大地震わせ
Make the earth shake,
過去を祝え
Celebrate the past,
明日を担え
Take on tomorrow!
命揺らせ 命揺らせ
Shake your life, shake your life!
大雨降らせ
Pour down heavy rain,
大地震わせ
Make the earth shake,
過去を祝え
Celebrate the past,
明日を担え
Take on tomorrow!
命揺らせ 命揺らせ
Shake your life, shake your life!
この時代に飛び乗って
Jump into this era,
今夜この街を飛び立って
Fly out of this town tonight,
大空を飛び回って
Flying around the vast sky.
命揺らせ 命揺らせ
Shake your life, shake your life!
この風に飛び乗って
Jump on this wind,
今夜タイフーンの目となって
Be the eye of the typhoon tonight,
大空を飛び回って
Flying around the vast sky.
命揺らせ 命揺らせ
Shake your life, shake your life!
貴女の期待に飛び乗って
Jump on your expectations,
今夜この羽根で飛びたくて
I want to fly with these wings tonight,
この大空を飛びたくて
I want to fly across this vast sky.
命生まれ 命生まれ
Born in life, born in life!
この風に飛び乗って
Jump on this wind,
今夜名もなき風となって
Becoming a nameless wind tonight,
清濁を併せ呑んで
Drinking purity and turbidity,
命揺らせ 命揺らせ
Shake your life, shake your life!
泡に乗って海を越え
Riding on foam across the sea,
季節をまた連れてくる
bringing the seasons along once more.
貝殻に耳澄ます
I listen closely to the seashell,
静寂にも声は探せ
searching for a voice even in the silence.
教えておくれ この風は
Tell me, where is this wind
どこから吹いているの
blowing from?
そこにいるの
Are you there?
時間よどうか待って 僕だけが祈っている
O time, please wait, I'm praying all alone.
生まれる前に 出会っていたよう
As if we had met before we were born,
寄せては返す 足跡も消して
erasing even the footprints washing ashore,
近づくほどに 遠ざかるあなた
you grow more distant the closer I get.
ヴィーナス 風にしたためた詩
Venus, a poem written on the wind!
眠れるように 握っては目覚め
As if sleeping, I grasp you and wake,
大人になれば ざわめきも消えて
and when I grow up, the commotion fades,
息づくほどに 遠のいていくもの
something drifting further away the more I breathe.
ヴィーナス いつか思い出す
Venus, I'll remember it someday!
生まれる前に 出会っていたよう
As if we had met before we were born,
寄せては返す 足跡も消して
erasing even the footprints washing ashore,
近づくほどに 遠ざかるあなた
you grow more distant the closer I get.
ヴィーナス 風にしたためた詩
Venus, a poem written on the wind!
眠れるように 握っては
As if sleeping, I grasp you
平気も計りにかけてまま
while still measuring my composure...
置いていくの 忘れるよ願って幸せを祈っている
Leaving it behind, wishing to forget and praying for happiness.
眠れるように 握っては目覚め
As if sleeping, I grasp you and wake,
大人になれば ざわめきも消えて
and when I grow up, the commotion fades,
息づくほどに 遠のいていくもの
something drifting further away the more I breathe.
ヴィーナス いつか思い出す
Venus, I'll remember it someday!
生まれる前に 出会っていたよう
As if we had met before we were born,
寄せては返す 足跡も消して
erasing even the footprints washing ashore,
近づくほどに 遠ざかるあなた
you grow more distant the closer I get.
ヴィーナス 風にしたためた詩
Venus, a poem written on the wind!
背が伸びた頃 きっと愛を
When I've grown taller, surely I'll find love,
砂に埋めた 涙も返して
returning even the tears buried in the sand.
生まれ変われど もう一度あなたの
Even if I'm reborn, once more your
ヴィーナス 微笑みと生きていたい
Venus, I want to live with your smile.
ヴィーナス 巡るあたたかな音
Venus, the warm sounds echoing around,
はーい、ということで始まりました！
Alright, and with that, it has begun!
音乃瀬奏生誕祭2026を見に来てくれてありがとうございます！ふー！
Thank you so much for coming to see Otonose Kanade's Birthday Festival 2026! Woo!
ちょっと駆け足でね、2曲お届けしましたが、いかがでしたでしょうか？
I delivered two songs rather quickly, so how was it?
たくさんコメントバチバチありがとー！
Thank you so much for all the rapid-fire comments!
見えてるよ、ありがとー！
I can see them, thank you!
はい、そしてね、ハッシュタグ、え、こちら、え、画面にも出ているんですが、音乃瀬奏生誕祭2026でいっぱいポストしてください！
Yes, and for the hashtag displayed on the screen, please post lots with #OtonoseKanadeBirthdayFestival2026!
ちょっとこの配信が終わったら、エゴサをするなり、いっぱいね、見に行くので、感想とか、ここが良かったよとかつぶやいてくれたらとっても嬉しいです！
Once this stream ends, I'll go ego-searching and check out so many of them, so if you tweet your thoughts, I'd be super happy!
ハッピーバースデーありがとう！ふー！
Happy birthday, thank you! Woo!
え、こちらの配信ですね、あの、タイトル、ライブのタイトル、IN PROGRESSというタイトルになっています。
This stream's title is "IN PROGRESS".
ちょっとね、どういう意味かなってお前らいっぱい推測してくれたと思うんですが、大体あってました！すごい！
I think you guys guessed a lot about what it means, and you were mostly right! Amazing!
こちらのタイトルですね、こちらの英語には、未完成という意味が…
This title—in English, it means "incomplete"...
という意味が込められていまして、ま、カラデのなんだろうな、今の
With that meaning imbued in it, um, Kanade's... how should I put it,
未完成ながら進むっていうスタンスをこのライブでお見せできればなと、思います。
unpolished yet moving forward stance—I hope I can show that off in this live.
はい、ちょっとまだ自分にこうなんだろう、完全に満足しきっていないけど、
Um, I'm not completely satisfied with myself just yet,
まだまだ止まらず今に安穏せず進んでいくぞっていう、そういう意味を込めての「In Progress」っていうタイトルにさせていただきました。
but with the meaning of not stopping, not resting easy, and pressing forward right now, I titled it "In Progress."
はーい。ま、ちょっとね、え、駆け足で、え、紹介していったということで、からでちょっとお水飲んで
Phew. Well, since I introduced everything rather quickly, um, I'd like to go drink some water...
いきたいんですけど、ダンサーさんたち！場をつないでもらったりしたりしますかね？
but, dancers! Could you guys fill in and keep the show going for a bit?
ねぇ！無理！
Hey! No way!
無理じゃない！やるんだよ！はい、お願いしまーす。
No "no way"! You're gonna do it! Yeah, please do!
なんか面白い動きとかいっぱいお願いします！
Give us lots of funny movements and stuff! Please!
ないしょはははは！
Secret! Hahaha!
え、ちょっとパワハラからねみたいな感じになりましたがですが、あの、普段ね、からでのダンスの指導をしてくださっているとっても親しい先生たちですよ、そうですよね？
Um, it turned into something like workplace harassment, but um, these are the very close teachers who usually guide Kanade's dance, right?
はい。言わせたみたいな。
Yeah. Making them say it.
じゃ、ちょっと今日の意気込み、なんか「うおー」とかで言ってもらったりできますか？
Well, can you give us your enthusiasm for today, maybe shouting something like "Woah!"?
頑張りまーす！いぇーい！
We'll do our best! Yay!
ダンサーさんたちもたくさんありがとうございます！
Thank you so much to the dancers too!
ではではでは、次はゲストパートになります。
Now then, next up will be the guest part.
最初は誰かな〜？ちょっと楽しみということで、じゃあ早速次の曲いきましょう！
Who could it be first~? I'm so excited, so let's go straight to the next song!
party is over
それでも踊りたかった
Still, I wanted to dance
眠れないくらい
To the point of not being able to sleep
情熱の日はいつしか
The fire of passion has vanished
いつの一日にか
Somewhere, sometime
はるから気づいている
I realized it from the very beginning
炎はいつか消える
My flame will fade away someday
何もいらないはずだった
I shouldn't have needed anything
なのにまだ I'm so serious
And yet, I'm still so serious
ああ まだ間に合う
Ah, there's still time
left with a broken heart
baby それなりそんなに甘くないよ
Baby, it's not going to be that sweet
でもきっとそんなに悪くないよ
But surely, it's not going to be that bad either
ああ give me fire!
Ah, give me fire!
燃やし尽くしちゃうぜ
Burn it all away
血を燃やして
Burning my blood,
変わりもせず人の形どうかし
without changing human shape, how's that?
全部燃やせよよし、いいだよ前を日のこと
Burn it all away, alright, look forward to the sun's days
突き切るのが仕事、決算にあとステロイド、漏るさもみると
Piercing through is my job, accounting plus steroids, seeing the leaks too
許すはしない、寝る今じゃできない
I won't forgive it, can't sleep right now
焦げたカルマドラマ燃え尽くすマグマドラマこの悪なき渇き渇き青い炎みたい
Scorched karma drama, burning out magma drama, this insatiable thirst, like a blue flame
差はここに1つとなりあげて捨てて1つとなりへ
The difference is right here as one, raising and casting away to become one
party is over
でもまだ消えてないから
But it hasn't faded away yet
忘れてみた
I tried forgetting
情熱の日はいつしか
The fire of passion has vanished
いつの一日にか
Somewhere, sometime
からだは気づいている
My body realized it
僕らはいつか消える
We will fade away someday
夜の若さを溶かして
Melting the youth of the night
泣かないで I'm so serious
Don't cry, I'm so serious
ああ まだ間に合う
Ah, there's still time
left with a broken heart
baby それなりそんなに甘くないよ
Baby, it's not going to be that sweet
でもきっとそんなに悪くないよ
But surely, it's not going to be that bad either
ああ give me fire!
Ah, give me fire!
燃やし尽くしちゃうぜ
Burn it all away
party is over
それでも踊りたかった
Even so, I wanted to dance.
眠れないくらい情熱の火は いつしかいつの日にか
The fire of passion, keeping me sleepless, someday, some day...
鼻から気づいている
Knowing from the very start,
ほむらはいつか消える
the flame will eventually fade.
ねえ何もいらないはずだった
Hey, I shouldn't have needed anything.
なのにまだ I'm so serious
And yet, I'm still so serious.
ああ まだ間に合う
Ah, there's still time.
ああ ただ Burn it up baby
Ah, just burn it up, baby!
盛り上がっていこうぜ yeah
Let's get hyped up, yeah!
party is over
それでも踊りたかった
Even so, I wanted to dance.
カリオペ先輩、お誕生日おめでとうございます！
Calliope-senpai, happy birthday!
Thank you very much!
カリオペガール！イエーイ！
Calliope girls! Yay!
Birthday girl!
まず最初のゲストは、カリオペ先輩に来てもらいましたー！
Our very first guest is Calliope-senpai!
初めまして。
Nice to meet you.
Hi everybody, yo yo, what's up? It's Mori Calliope here today to celebrate Kanade's special birthday, yo!
カナデの誕生日を！お祝いに来てくれたじゃん！
To celebrate Kanade's birthday! You came to celebrate!
祝いに来てくれてじゃあ、ありがとございます。
Thank you so much for coming to celebrate.
いやー、めっちゃ緊張してた。
Man, I was so nervous.
ラップする前、やばい、やばい、できない、できない、できないって
Right before rapping, I was like, "Oh no, oh no, I can't do this!"
いやいやいや、めちゃくち、感じなかったですよ、そんな。
No, no, no, it didn't feel like that at all!
いや、難しい日本語のラップかっこよくなんか
Well, rapping in difficult Japanese...
頑張りました！
I did my best!
いや、かっこよかったですよ、もうなんか...ねえ。かっこよかったよ。
No, it was so cool, you know... It was really cool.
え、うれし？ 一緒にいい感じになりました、いえーい。
Eh, really? We made a great vibe together, yay!
一緒にうたいりたかったんですよー。
I wanted to sing together with you so badly.
私も...
Me too...
カリオペ先輩のラップが大好きで、あのBeyond the Stageでも実は歌ってみたのね。
I love Calliope-senpai's rap so much, and I actually tried singing it at Beyond the Stage too.
で、ご一緒にさせていただたりとかしまして、それ以来じゃないか？
And we got to perform together, so isn't it been since then?
そうですね、あんまり、うん、機会がなくて。
That's right, we haven't had many opportunities since.
そうですね。でも今回はすごかった。
Yeah, but this time was amazing.
うれし！ぶちかました！
Yay! We crushed it!
いやかっこいい、それからもやりたいけど、今スタミナからできないよ。
It was so cool. I'd love to do it again, but I'm out of stamina right now!
の、の、の、スタミナ、スタミナがもうして、先輩、ありがとございます。
Stamina, my stamina is gone. Senpai, thank you so much.
お水いっぱい飲んで。
Drink lots of water.
はい、ありが、あ、お水飲みに行ってこようかな。
Yes, thanks... Ah, I think I'll go drink some water.
Hi everybody, Kanade-chan, water time, what's up? I'm Mori Calliope!
プラプラプラ、あぶら！できた！
Bla-bla-bla, abura! I did it!
いや、ちょっと忘れちゃおうと思ってたけど、できた。
Man, I thought I might forget it, but I did it.
もう、生、生歌すごい好きだから、今回誘ってくれてありがとうございます。
I really love live vocals, so thank you so much for inviting me this time.
いやこちらこそありがとうございます、本当に！
No, thank you so much, truly!
一緒に歌えてすごく光栄でした。
It was such an honor to sing together.
またやろう！私でよければ！ご一緒させてください！
Let's do it again! If you'll have me, please let me join you!
やりましょう！ということで、カリオペ先輩、ありがとうございましたー！
Let's do it! So, Calliope-senpai, thank you so much!
ありがとうございました！
Thank you very much!
これから頑張ってね、Good luck! You can do it! Thank very much, peace, bye-bye!
Do your best from now on! Good luck! You can do it! Thank you very much, peace, bye-bye!
ということで、カリオペ先輩との火炎でした！
And that was "Kaen" with Calliope-senpai!
次の曲行く前にちょっと暑いから、ちょっと着替えてきてもいいですか？
Before going to the next song, it's a bit hot, so do you mind if I go change my clothes?
ちょっと待っててくださいね。
Please wait just a moment.
ふう...
Phew...
ちょっとジャケット脱いできました！ちょっと熱気がね、すごい！
I took off my jacket! The heat in here is incredible!
お前らもいっぱい、書き、ありがとう、ありがとうございます、コメント見えてるよ！
Thank you all so much for all the comments, I can see them!
では、さっそく次の曲行きましょうかね。ゲスト誰か、楽しみですね。
Now then, let's head right into the next song. I wonder who the guest is, I'm so excited.
では、聞いてください。
Now, please listen.
語れない 眠れない トロイメライ
Unable to speak, unable to sleep, a daydream.
あなたの見てる正体は一体
What is the true form you are looking at?
誰も読めないカルテ 謎を知りたいだけ
A chart no one can read, I just want to know the mystery.
不思議 知りたいだけ
The mystery, I just want to know.
嘘も現実も どっちも真実だったの本当よ
Both lies and reality were true, truly.
今日もひとりごと
Talking to myself again today,
なににも無理をしないで 私愛されたい
don't force anything, I want to be loved.
有効無効 さよなら 軽い眩暈
Valid or invalid, goodbye, a light dizziness.
あなたのいない現象界 誰もしれないカルテ
A phenomenal world without you, a chart no one can read.
自意識 溢れ出して
Self-consciousness overflowing,
心拍 世界像 いつも噛み合わないの 痛くて
heartbeat and worldview never align, it hurts.
毎夜ねがいごと
Every night, making a wish,
なにも疑わないで 混ざり溶け合いたい
without doubting anything, I want to melt together.
たわいない 分からない 理由 存在 あなたと残す後悔
Silly, unknown reasons and existence, regrets left behind with you.
誰もしれないカルテ 不快 繰り返して
A chart no one can read, repeating discomfort.
正しい夢は かなしい声は
Correct dreams, sad voices...
誰も読めないカルテ 不可思議 知りたいだけ
A chart that no one can read, I just want to know the mystery
語れない 眠れない トロメライ
I cannot speak, I cannot sleep, stuck in a daydream
あなたの 見てる正体
The true form you see...
誰も 読めない カルテ
A chart that no one can read
不可思議 知りたいだけ
I just want to know the mystery
嘘も 現実も どっちも真実だったの本当に
Both lies and reality, both were true, really
今日もひとりごと なににも無理をしないで
Talking to myself again today, don't force anything
有耶無耶 さよなら 軽い眩暈 あなたのいない 現象界
Ambiguous goodbye, light dizziness, the phenomenal world without you
誰も読めないカルテ 自己意識溢れ出して
A chart that no one can read, overflowing self-consciousness
鼓動 世界像 いつも噛み合わないの 痛くて
Heartbeat, world view, our teeth never quite align, it hurts
毎夜寝言 なににも疑わないで 混ぜ合いたい
Every night, murmuring in sleep, don't doubt anything, I want to mix together
たわいない 分からない 理由 存在 あなたと残す後悔
Silly, unknown, reasons, existence, the regrets left with you
正しい夢は かなしい声は 美しい？ 疑わしい？ 羨ましい？ ねぇ、どれ？
Correct dreams, sad voices, is it beautiful? doubtful? envious? hey, which one?
語れない 眠れない トロメライ
I cannot speak, I cannot sleep, stuck in a daydream
あなたの 見てる正体
The true form you see...
誰も読めないカルテ 不可思議 知りたいだけ
A chart that no one can read, I just want to know the mystery
終わらないこと はないトロメライ あなたと跨ぐ境界
There's no end, stuck in a daydream, the boundary where you cross with me
誰も読めないカルテ 思春期 痲痺 胸のうち 不可思議 知りたいだけ
A chart that no one can read, adolescence, numbness, inner feelings, I just want to know the mystery
誰も読めないカルテ 思春期 傷口 胸のうじ 不可思議 知りたいだけ
A chart that no one can read, adolescence, wounds, inner feelings, I just want to know the mystery
不可思議 知りたいだけ
I just want to know the mystery
はーいということで
Alright, so...
2時3時からまちたちばささんに来ていただきましたー！
We had Machi Tachibana-san join us from 2:00 to 3:00!
お前らの皆さんこんばんは！上から読んでも下から読んでもまちたちばまでーす！
Good evening, everyone! Whether read from top or bottom, I'm Machi Tachibana!
イェーイ！
Yay!
ちばさんにもお前らが浸透して、もちろん知っています
Tachibana-san, the fans have really caught on with you, of course you know.
知ってるんですか？お誕生日をお迎えしたということで、もちろん知ってて... すごいめでたいね！めでたいですよね！
You know? Since it's your birthday, of course we knew... That's so wonderful! It really is!
いや、つい、やっちゃうんですこれ。
No, I just end up doing that.
あ、やっちゃう。くせなんですか？くせなんです。
Ah, you do? Is it a habit? It's a habit.
それちょっとリハーサルの時もやってた。
You were doing that even during rehearsals.
やめて、ばらすの！やめてください！変な動きが出ちゃうんですよね。
Stop exposing me! Please stop! Weird movements just come out.
でも今日はちょっとおとなしくね、お話しします。
But today, I'll talk a bit more calmly.
なるほど。ちょっと出てましたけど、全然出していただいて大丈夫ですからね。
I see. It was coming out a bit, but it's totally fine if you let it out.
あの、そういえばちばさんとですね、先月一緒に「空想列車」という楽曲の歌ってみたをね、コラボさせていただいて。
Oh, come to think of it, Tachibana-san and I collaborated on a cover of the song "Kusou Ressha" last month.
私こそ誘っていただいて本当に嬉しかったです。
I was honestly so happy you invited me.
そうですか？やったやった。
Is that so? Yay, yay!
からでもちばさんの透明な歌声に絶対合うだろうなって思って、空想列車もそうだし今回の不可思議のカルテも絶対に合うだろうなって思って選曲させていただいたんですよ。
I thought your clear singing voice would definitely match it, so I chose "Kusou Ressha" and "Fukashigi no Carte" this time too.
嬉しい！一緒に歌えてとっても嬉しいです！すごく幸せです！
I'm so happy! I'm so happy we could sing together! I'm so blessed!
え、もうからでなんか1個気になってることがあって、何でしょう？空想列車のコメント欄に、なんか「化け物」って書いてあったんですけど、ちばさんのこと。
Um, Kanade, there's one thing I've been curious about. In the comments of "Kusou Ressha", someone wrote "monster" referring to you.
それは何なんですか？
What is that about?
多分別人、の、違う人のこと言ってるのかなって思うので、忘れてください。
They probably mean a different person, so please forget about it.
わかりました！あ、ちが、そんな、そんな綺麗な、ねえ！
Understood! Ah, no, such... such a pretty, hey!
そうだよ、こんなもう、化け物なわけないですよ。ね？今のコメントでも化け物って書いてあったけど、きっとちょっと見間違えてますよね、これ。
That's right, there's no way I'm a monster. Right? Even in the current comments it said "monster", but they must have misread it.
見間違えた。ほんで、我々体も清楚でね。もちろん体も清楚ですよ、そりゃあもう！
Misread it. And our bodies are pure, too. Of course our bodies are pure, absolutely!
はい、ということでちばさんと一緒に歌えてとっても嬉しかったです！こちらこそ嬉しかった！嬉しかったです！よかったらまた機会があったらまた一緒に歌わせてくだい！
Yes, so I was very happy to sing with Tachibana-san! I was so happy too! If there's another chance, please let me sing with you again!
いつでも歌いましょう！
Let's sing anytime!
やったー！げんじとりましたー！やったやった、嬉しい。
Yay! We got it done! Yay, yay, I'm happy.
じゃあこの後も引き続き頑張ってください！ありがとうございます！嬉しかったです！また！
Well, please keep doing your best after this too! Thank you! I was so happy! See you!
ということで、ちょっとからでもお水を飲んできてもいいですか?
So, is it okay if I go grab a quick drink of water?
ちょっとだけお水飲んできます。
I'll be right back with some water.
まだまだまだまだ続いていきますよ。
It's still going to keep going and going!
次は誰かしら? あと2人ですね。
Who's next? Just two more left.
1/2の確率、それでは楽しみに待ってて下さい。次の曲。
A 50-50 chance. Look forward to it. The next song...
いくぞ!
Let's go!
あれが正解なんて
Who says that's right?
誰の成れの果て?
Whose shadow of their former self?
答えも欲しいのも一個でこれだけ
I just want an answer, just this one thing
悩んだってしょうがないじゃんね
There's no point in worrying about it anyway
あれは夢だったって思うことにしたって
I decided to think of that as just a dream
でも全然思えないんだけどさ
But I really can't see it that way at all, so
助けてよフォロワー!
Help me, followers!
抵抗だけ
Just resisting
若さに負け
Yielding to youth
next, next, lucky, lucky & lucky!
oh+eh+oh 割り切れちゃったらさ
Oh+eh+oh If I could just break it down
oh+eh+oh 楽なのだろうけど
Oh+eh+oh It would be so easy, but
ああもうヤダ!
Ah, I'm already done with this!
なんていう新世界か!
What a brave new world!
あなた以外はあなた以外はいらないいらない
Except for you, I don't need anyone else at all!
はらないでよバリアあるはずなのは何か
Don't put up a barrier, there should be something there
あったならば
If there is,
happy, jumpin', yeah!
あなたのその手とあたしのこの手を
Your hand and my hand,
つないだらもう二度と離さないわ
Once we hold on, I'll never let go again
あなたのその手があたしのこの手を
Your hand grabbing my hand
掴んだら以降お見知り置きを my love♡
Please remember me from now on, my love♡
これで終わりなんて
This is the end, you say?
アガれないままなんて
And it's just going to stay like this?
どうにかなってちゃって願って願って
Wishing and hoping it'll turn out somehow
ねぇ朝帰りしたりしちゃいわゆ? どう?
Hey, why don't we stay out all night? How about it?
なぁもう我慢できん!
Ah, I can't stand it anymore!
pain, pain 痛いってば everyday
Pain, pain, it hurts everyday
ま、ゆーていけるけどなブルベ夏なんて関係ないな^^
Well, I can get by, but summer type doesn't matter at all^^
誰よりもネコ節操ない! も結構
More than anyone, I have no integrity! That's fine too
あーしはあーしだ見といてよ ready
I am who I am, just watch me, ready
もう今日で終わらせたいなって
I want to end it today
リスタートできたらって
If I could just restart
でも無理だよもう~~~~~!
But it's impossible, I'm already...
what's on your mind?
oh+eh+oh 割り切れちゃったらさ
Oh+eh+oh If I could just break it down
oh+eh+oh 楽なのだろうけど
Oh+eh+oh It would be so easy, but
ああもうヤダ!
Ah, I'm already done with this!
なんていう新世界か!
What a brave new world!
あなた以外はあなた以外はいらないいらない
Except for you, I don't need anyone else at all!
はらないでよバリアあるはずなのは何か
Don't put up a barrier, there should be something there
あったならば
If there is,
happy, jumpin', yeah!
あなたのその手とあたしのこの手を
Your hand and my hand,
つないだらもう二度と離さないわ
Once we hold on, I'll never let go again
あなたのその手があたしのこの手を
Your hand grabbing my hand
掴んだら以降お見知り置きを my love♡
Please remember me from now on, my love♡
あなたのその手とあたしのこの手を
Your hand and my hand,
つないだらもう二度と離さないわ
Once we hold on, I'll never let go again
あなたのその手があたしのこの手を
Your hand grabbing my hand
掴んだら以降お見知り置きを my love♡
Please remember me from now on, my love♡
はい、なんと3人目のゲストは、同じく23時からいぬいとこさんに来ていただきました!
Yes, and our third guest is Inui Toko-san, joining us from 11 PM!
いぬいとこです。 いぬいとこ! いぬいとこです。 いぬいとこ、いぬいとこ。
I'm Inui Toko. Inui Toko! I'm Inui Toko. Inui Toko, Inui Toko.
いぬいと、いぬいとこ。いー
Inui to, Inui Toko. I—
えへ、難しいよ。
Hehe, it's hard!
いいよ、好きに呼んでいいですよ。いぬいたそ!
It's fine, you can call me whatever you like! Inuitaso!
お誕生日おめでとうございます! お誕生日おめでとう!
Happy birthday! Happy birthday!
ありがとうございます! Happy Birthday!
Thank you so much! Happy Birthday!
Nice to meet you. Nice to meet you too.
初めましてじゃない。
We've met before, you know.
初めましてですよ。
This is our first time meeting!
今日初めて会いました。
We met for the first time today.
今日ガチの初めまして。
Today is genuinely our first time meeting.
いつの今日ガチの初めましては私じゃなくて。
Today's genuinely first meeting isn't with me...
ないないない、今日初めまして。
No, no, no, we're meeting for the first time today.
初めまして。ちょっと。
Nice to meet you. Wait.
ねえ、ちまさんとは空想列車の歌ってみたでご一緒させていただいたんですけど、本当の本当の今日初めて初めまして。
Hey, I sang 'Kuso Ressha' with Chima-san, but today is genuinely our very first time meeting in person.
はい、もう今日初めて会った時、あの、とこさんが楽屋に来ていただいて、挨拶に来ていただいて、ありがとうございます。
Yes, and when we first met today, Toko-san came to my dressing room to greet me, thank you very much.
で、その時に、お弁当が控室にあったから、あ、よかったらお弁当食べますかって言って、あの選んでください。カレーだったんですけど、カレーとなんか付随するものがあるお弁当だったんで
And at that time, since there were bento boxes in the dressing room, she asked, 'Would you like some bento if you'd like?' and told me to choose. It was curry, and a bento box that came with some sides...
すけど、
...is, but
なんか、とこさんが一言放ったんですよ。
Toko said something.
「芋だ！」って。
"Imo da!" ("Yam!")
お芋が大好きなんです、私。
I love yams, you see.
お芋？
Yam?
お芋めっちゃ好きなんですよ。
I really love yams.
カレーなのに、お芋？
Yam, even though it's curry?
お芋が好きやから。
Because I love yams!
「お芋好きなんだ」って思って、
Thinking "Oh, I love yams,"
お芋があるお弁当だったから、あっよかったーって思って、
it was a bento with yams in it, so I thought, "Yay!"
じゃあちょっと、お芋一番大きいのを選びますねって言って。
"Then I'll choose the biggest yam," I said.
そう、かなでチョイスでね。
Kanade's choice, right?
選んで、別にそれをこうあげようとしたわけじゃないんですけど、
And I chose it, not that I was trying to give it to her or anything, but...
とこさんが、そう採用してくださって。
Toko-san, you accepted it!
いや、それはスルーでしょ！
No, I'd skip that!
そんなだてせっかくこれ一番お芋大きいですよって選んでくれたら、じゃあこれで行って言って。
"Since you chose this as the biggest yam, I'll take this," you said!
じゃあこれでって言って。
"Then I'll take this," you said!
じゃあこれで召し上がりますって言って。
"I'll take this one," you said!
めちゃくちゃ嬉しかったんです。
I was so happy!
あれ、なんかいろんな味あったんですけども、お芋の大きさだけで選んでましたよね？
There were all kinds of yams, but you chose it just based on the size, right?
違うよ、ちがうちがう。かなだが選んでくれたから、
No, no, Kanade chose it for me!
持ってったんだよ、私は。
I took it!
感動しました。
I was touched.
そうなんですか？
Is that so?
そうよ。
Yeah, I love them.
大好物。
I love them so much.
よかったの、あの。
So I'm glad...
今後もし何か機会があったら、もちろん、なんか一緒にやりましょう。
So if we ever have the chance again, of course, we'll do it together.
いくらでもやろう一緒に。
We'll do whatever together!
本当ですか？ユニットも組むんですか？
Really? What about a unit?
もうなんでもやろう！全部やろう！やりたいこと全部やろう！
Let's do everything! Let's do all of it! Let's do everything we want to do!
本当ですか？やった！
Really? Yay!
ユニット名、
Unit name?
かなですで。
Kanade's?
ちょっとかぶるか。
Let's cover it up a bit.
Let's cover it up.
っていう冗談でなんか一緒にできたら嬉しいですね。スーパー！
And saying "Yam!" we can do it together, I'd be so happy, Super!
ありがとうございますと言って、とこさん。
Thank you so much, Toko-san.
ありがとうございます！
Thank you!
私も楽しみにしてました。
I was looking forward to it too.
一緒にポーズして、バイバーイ！
Let's do the duo pose together, bye-bye!
バイバーイ！
Bye-bye!
ということでですね、次がゲストは最後になります。
So with that said, the next guest will be our last.
最後あの人って、みんなわかるよねー！
The last person is... I'm sure you all know!
楽しみにしていてください。
Please look forward to it.
それでは、次の曲行きます！
Well then, let's go to the next song!
浪漫と算盤
"Roman to Sannban"
作詞・作曲: 椎名林檎
Lyrics/Composition: Shiina Ringo
主義をもって利益を成した場合ほ
When profit is accomplished as a principle,
商いが食い扶持以上の意味を宿す
Business has more meaning than the cost of one's food
義務と権利双方を重んじつつ飽くまで
While honoring both duty and rights,
両者割合は曖昧にして居たい
I want to keep both ratios vague until the bitter end
玄人衆と素人衆皆の衆酸鼻論調だ
Experts, amateurs, and everybody else, please give me the pros and cons
理屈を頂戴置き場に行くおぞ野暮新しき技毎回繰り返したいです
Fearing a challenge and taking the easy way is dumb
苦しくとも僕には解き分かっているあなたも同様に独り生きている
No matter how painful, I understand; just like me, you too live alone
宇宙を因数分解したところで自由と孤独だけが待っているんでしょう
Once you've factorized the universe, only freedom and loneliness will be waiting
玄人で素人で労働者で生活者のままで
Experts and amateurs and laborers, I'm still an ordinary citizen
面白い可笑しく居させて煩わしい役毎回請け負いたいです無私なくとも
Let me stay humorous. I want to undertake the troublesome roles every time, even if it's fruitless
あなたを想うたび僕は許されて行く夢と現実を繋いで
Whenever I think of you, I'm excused, binding together my dreams and reality
きっと思そう浪漫抱けたら算盤弾いて
Surely once we embrace romance, we should use the abacus
両極のど真ん中狙い撃ってお願い勇気を御拝借
And aim for the very middle of the two extremes, so please give me courage...
疑わしい相手なら何時だって自分ずーっと進化したいのね答え合わせ
If it's a suspicious opponent, then I want to evolve forever. Let's check our answers
あなたを知る程僕は正されて行く捨てたもんじゃない只生きようとして
The more I know you, the more I'm corrected. That's pretty impressive; I'll just try living
主義をもって利益を成した場合ほ
When profit is accomplished as a principle,
商いが食い扶持以上の意味を宿す
Business has more meaning than the cost of one's food
義務と権利双方を重んじつつ飽くまで
While honoring both duty and rights,
両者割合は曖昧にして居たい
I want to keep both ratios vague until the bitter end
あなたを想うたび僕は許されて行く夢とうつつを繋いで
Whenever I think of you, I'm excused, binding together my dreams and reality
きっとそろばん抱えたら そのばん弾いて
If you hold an abacus, strike it right then and there.
両極のど真ん中 狙い撃って
Aim right down the middle of both extremes.
お願い 勇気をくれ
I beg you, give me courage.
いつだって自分 ずっと進化したいよね
No matter what, you always want to keep evolving, right?
答え合わせ 貴方を知るほど 僕は正されて行く
Checking our answers, the more I know you, the more I'm corrected.
僕はただされてく すべてかものじゃ無い ただ生きようと
I'm just being corrected, not that everything is certain—just trying to live.
息をとおして...
Breathing through...
うわー！
Whoa!
マイクが遠いぞ！
The mic is far away!
体触れた！
Our bodies touched!
なんてタフな持ち方
What a tough way to hold it!
ロッカーでしょ？
Like a rocker, right?
イェーイ！イェーイ！
Yay! Yay!
いやいいですね スタンドマイクかっこいいじゃないですか
Man, this is great. Stand mics look so cool, don't they?
カッコいいっすよね！
So cool!
ね、おめでとうございます本当に出
Right? Congratulations, truly!
ありがとうございます！
Thank you so much!
Thank you!
これちょっと受けるの もう一回いこう
Let's take that again, that was funny. Let's do it again.
せーの！
Ready, go!
ありがとうございます！
Thank you very much!
はい、ということで最後のゲストは
Yes, so our final guest is...
星街すいせいちゃんでした！
Hoshimachi Suisei-chan!
はい、ありがとうございます！呼んでくださって、推しのこと... 星街すいせいバーチャルアイドルの星街すいせいです。皆さんこんにちは！
Yes, thank you so much for inviting me! As my oshi... I'm Hoshimachi Suisei, virtual idol Hoshimachi Suisei. Hello everyone!
こんにちは！
Hello!
音の瀬の皆さんなんですよね？
You're Otonose's fans, right?
あ、はい、そうです！音の瀬の正式名称...
Ah, yes, that's right! Otonose's official name...
正式名称？
Official name?
えだのすけ... 素晴らしい！
Edanosuke... That's amazing!
ね、音の瀬の皆さんいつも思えらと言われていますけれども！
Right? You're always told you're amazing by Otonose's fans!
はい！
Yes!
いやもう今回の「ロマンのそろばん」...「ロマンとそろばん」っていう楽曲
Man, this song "Roman to Soroban"...
すいちゃん先輩と一緒に歌ったら絶対にカッコいいだろうって思って
I thought singing "Roman to Soroban" together with Suisei-senpai would definitely be so cool, so...
まあカッコいいけどさ、生でやるもんじゃないよね！
Well, it's cool, but not something to do live!
もう私...
I really...
もう私、昨日とかさ、「うたえる？うたえる？うたえるのかしら？」ってめちゃめちゃ不安だったけど
Yesterday and all I was super nervous thinking, "Can I sing it? Can I sing it? Can I really sing it?"
今日合わせてみてね、
But practicing together today...
よかったじゃん。
It went well, right?
よかったですよね。
It went well.
めちゃめちゃ美声でしたよ。めちゃめちゃ美声でしたよ、かなで。
It was such a beautiful voice. Such a beautiful voice, Kanade.
ありがとう！え、うれぴー！
Thank you! Yay, I'm so happy!
ね、ほらコメント欄もね。
Right, look at the comment section too.
うん、めちゃめちゃよかった、めっっちゃよかった、うん。
Yeah, it was super good, really good, yeah.
めちゃめちゃ、え、相性よかった。ほら、相性よかったって。
Super... our chemistry was great. Look, they say our chemistry was great.
うれしい〜！
I'm so happy!
よかったらまた歌ってこなさいよ、一緒に。
If you'd like, come sing with me again sometime.
え、そうそう、なんか2人だけで歌うのは初めてなんだよね。
Ah, right, singing just the two of us is actually a first.
そうなんです。パンドラヒーローでなんか4人で一緒に歌うっていうことはあったんですけど、今回2人きりは初めてということで。
That's right. With Pandora Hero we've sung together as four, but this is the first time just the two of us.
ね、すごい楽しかったですし。
It was a lot of fun.
またね、呼んでくださいかなでちゃん。キャンマチャンのためなら飛んできますよ。
Please invite me again, Kanade-chan. For Kanayama-chan, I'll fly right over.
生でハモリっていうすごい難しい難題を一緒に飛び越えられて... 飛び越えたね！
Overcoming such a difficult challenge like live harmonies together... We crossed it!
嬉しかったね！頑張りました私たち！
We're so happy! We did our best, both of us!
是非ともね、アーカイブ残るしね、何回も見返してほしいですね。
Please, the archive will stay, so I hope you'll rewatch it many times.
はい、ぜひ！ということでかなでちゃんこの後もまだまだ続くと思いますが、頑張ってください！
Yes, absolutely! So Kanade-chan, I know there's still more to come after this, do your best!
ありがとうございます！本当にありがとうございました！ありがとうございました！
Thank you so much! Thank you truly! Thank you!
ありがとうございましたー！それでは失礼します！
Thank you very much! Well then, excuse me!
はーい、ありがとうございましたー！
Bubbly! Thank you very much!
さあ、ゲストの皆さんにね、たくさん盛り上げていただきましたということで、ここからはソロでですね、え、頑張っていきますよっていうことで。
Now, our guests really hyped things up for us, so from here on out, I'll be going solo and doing my best!
まだまだまだまだ盛り上げていきます！
I'll keep getting you even more hyped up!
その前にちょっと準備とお水を飲んでくるので待っててください！行ってきまーす！
Before that, I'm going to prepare and drink some water, so please wait for me! I'll be right back!
ここからは一気に5曲行っちゃいます！
From here on out, we're going straight through 5 songs!
最後にさ、
Now lastly,
シークレットだもん。最後のお楽しみにということで。
it's a secret. As a final treat for you,
それでは次の曲聞いてください。
so please listen to the next song.
All Alone With You
誰かを愛することなんてできないわけなくって
There's no way I could never love someone else,
だけど誰かに愛されたくて
but I want someone to love me.
変わらない昨日がずっと続いたとしても
And even if yesterday went on never changing,
どこにも行けやしないんだ
we can't go anywhere at all,
私とキミ
you and I.
神様 どこへ行ってしまったのね 答えはなくて いつだってそうだよ
Lord in heaven, where have you gone to? Please, you never respond to me.
Are you still here?
You'll never walk alone
あなたと行く
I'll go with you.
どんな罪も
No matter your sin,
背負ってあげる
I'll shoulder it for you.
Are you still here?
You're never walk alone
You'll never walk alone
道なき道を歩いてくの あなたと
I'll walk the unpaved paths all alone with you.
二人で 私に触れて キスをして
Come here, touch me, kiss me.
もっとめちゃくちゃにしたっていいんだよ?
It's okay for you to mess me up even more, you know?
ここにきて 私に触れて キスをして
Come here, touch me, kiss me.
もっとめちゃくちゃにしたっていいんだよ?
It's okay for you to mess me up even more, you know?
いつか誰もが死んじゃって 忘れられてくなら 今確かなものだけを信じるわ
Everyone will die one day. If I'm going to be forgotten, right now, I'll believe only in something concrete.
神様 気取りの人が言うの
Lord in heaven, pretentious people say,
ねえ 人は強いって そんなの嘘だよ
"Hey, it's a total lie that people are strong."
Do you agree?
I will stay with you
あなたの手で 抱きしめてよ
Embrace me in your arms with all your strength.
思いっきり 怖がらないで もう大丈夫 私なら
Don't be afraid, you know me, I'm fine now.
その手が 汚れてしまってとしても
Even if your hands are stained beyond cleansing,
愛してほしい 私のこと
I want you to love me.
You're never walk alone
You'll never walk alone
あなたと行く
I'll go with you.
どんな罪も
No matter your sin,
背負ってあげる 道なき道を
I'll shoulder it for you. I'll walk the unpaved paths
歩いてくの あなたと
all alone with you.
I will stay with you
あなたの手で 抱きしめてよ
Embrace me in your arms with all your strength.
暖かい涙で
With warm tears,
ふいに目覚めた
I suddenly woke up.
焦がれた夢の続きは何処にあるの
Where is the sequel of the dream I longed for?
寂しいよ
How lonely I am...
please, give it back
いつになれば楽になれる
When will I finally find peace?
押し返しては波に抗って
Fighting against the pushing waves,
白い枕に
I bury my face
寝惚けたままの顔を埋めて
into the white, half-asleep pillow.
同じ夢を願うほどに苛まれていくよ
The more I pray for the same dream, the more I'm tormented.
please, give it back
代わりなんてないよ あなたの匂い
There's no replacement for you, your scent...
思い出せない 波にさらわれて
I can't remember it, swept away by the waves.
夢の続きを捕まえにいくから待ってて
I'm going to catch the sequel of my dream, so just wait for me.
いつの間にか孤独ぶるには優しさに触れ過ぎた沁み行く
Before I realized, when I pretended to be lonely, I had been touched too much by gentleness...
顔上げてみようか
Shall I try lifting my face?
ひとりじゃないって信じてみたい信じてみたいの
I want to believe I'm not alone, I want to believe it.
give it a shot
生まれたばかりの淡い光に
In the faint light that was just born,
希望を見たの胸が熱いよ
I saw hope, my heart feels so warm.
手を握っていて迷わないように明日からまた
Keep holding my hand so I won't get lost, starting tomorrow once again...
選んだ道を進めるように
So I can walk the path I chose.
please, give it back
変わりなんてないよ
There's no replacement...
あなたの匂い思い出せない
I can't remember your scent.
波にさらわれて
Swept away by the waves.
夢の続きを捕まえにいくから待ってて
I'm going to catch the sequel of my dream, so just wait for me.
いつの間にか孤独ぶるには優しさに触れ過ぎた
Before I realized, when I pretended to be lonely, I had been touched too much by gentleness.
顔上げてみようか
Shall I try lifting my face?
ひとりじゃないって信じてみたい信じてみたいの
I want to believe I'm not alone, I want to believe it.
give it a shot
生まれたばかりの
Born just now...
淡い光に希望を見たの胸が熱いよ
In the faint light I saw hope, my heart feels so warm.
手を握っていて
Keep holding my hand...
迷わないように
So I won't get lost.
明日からまた
From tomorrow once again...
選んだ道を進めるように
So I can walk the path I chose.
ぶつかって逃げ込んで
Got smacked around, had to back down,
僕はいつしかここに立ってただ
somehow, now where I am ain't far from where I began.
誰かが憧れるヒーローに
I tried to be the hero everyone looked up to,
なりたくて でもなれなくて
but I could never be him.
これくらいじゃ届かないこと分かっていたのに
It's not enough, I always knew.
敗北の少年 現実を詛え
The boy defeated knows fact from fiction.
あんな風に空は飛べやしないんだ
A man in tights can't fly off into the night.
こんな夜に意味があるなら
And if there's meaning up in the starry sky,
僕らは地を這う
we will crawl on hands and knees.
耳鳴りがこだまして 僕に奇跡が問いかけるんだ
I feel my heartbeat, and ground beneath my feet.
「君の夢 憧れたヒーローに今すぐ させてあげよう」
"Let's make your dream come true right now."
飴みたいに差し出されたって 嬉しくないんだ
I've had enough, I just give up.
敗北の少年 存在を詛え
To all the ones who don't believe that there's a heaven above,
君みたいに眩しくはなれないけど
this is a story without a happy end.
こんな夜に意味があるなら
Say goodbye now.
僕らは地を這う まだ地を這う
We are the ones who flew with wings that melted off in the sun.
鼓動を知って 息を吸い込んで
I feel my heartbeat, and ground beneath my feet.
「僕は遠慮するよ」
I've had enough, I just give up.
敗北の少年 平凡を詛え
To all the ones who don't believe that there's a heaven above,
あいだくろ 神は信じないタチで
this is a story without a happy end.
すれ違いの物語よ さようなら
Say goodbye now.
敗北の少年 現実を詛え
We are the ones who flew with wings that melted off in the sun.
僕らは泥を 陰り蹲るもの
And though there's beauty up in the starry sky,
こんな夜も愛しいから
we will crawl on hands and knees.
僕らは地を這う ただ地を這う
We will crawl on hands and knees.
鼓動を知って 息を吸い込んで
I feel my heartbeat, and ground beneath my feet.
僕は遠慮するよ
I've had enough, I just give up.
敗北の少年 敗北の少年
To all the ones who don't believe that there's a heaven above,
何度を耐え
this is a story without a happy end.
逢いに行くのと 神は信じないたちで
Say goodbye now.
すれ違いの 物語よ
We are the ones who flew with wings that melted off in the sun.
さようなら
And though there's beauty up in the starry sky,
敗北の少年 現実を耐え
we will crawl on hands and knees.
僕らは泥を這い蹲るもの
We will crawl on hands and knees.
こんな夜も 愛しいから
僕らは地を這う ただ地を這う
We will crawl on hands and knees.
あのね。 I say “私、大丈夫？”
Hey, I say 'Am I okay?'
Maybe、うまくやれるはず
Maybe, I should be able to do it well.
ずっと走った息継ぎもしないまま
Running all the way without even taking a breath.
あっそう、
Oh I see...
終わりが来るなら
If the end is coming,
別に寂しくなんかはない
I'm not particularly lonely.
真実は心の奥の方
The truth is deep in my heart.
自分のことすら愛せないまま 君のこと守れるのかな
While I can't even love myself, I wonder if I can protect you.
“信じて”
'Believe me...'
どうかし、正真正銘のこの想いを聴いて
Somehow, please listen to this true thought.
私、全身全霊で歌うから
I will sing with all my heart and soul.
大丈夫、世界はこんなに綺麗だと
It's okay, I know the world is this beautiful.
分かってる、分かってる、解ってる…わかってるよ！
I know, I know, I understand... I know it!
ごめんね。じれったい
I'm sorry. It's frustrating.
足りない、こんなんじゃ誰も愛せないの
It's not enough, I can't love anyone like this.
止めない、止まることは知らないの
I won't stop, I don't know how to stop.
言葉足らず、失くしてしまう物ばかりだ
It's only words that are lacking, and things I'll lose.
あのね。
Hey,
i say “私、大丈夫？”
I say, "Am I okay?"
maybe,
うまくやれるはず
I should be able to do it well.
ずっと走った息継ぎもしないまま
I kept running without even catching my breath.
あっそう、終わりが来るなら
Oh, I see. If the end is coming,
別に寂しくなんかないな
I'm not particularly lonely.
真実 心の奥の方
The truth is buried deep in my heart,
自分のことすら愛せないまま
Unable to even love myself.
君のこと守れるのかな
I wonder if I can protect you.
“信じて”
"Believe me."
どうか、正真正銘のこの思いを聴いて、
Please, listen to my heartfelt feelings.
私、全身全霊で歌うから
I will sing with all my heart.
大丈夫、世界はこんなに綺麗だと
It's okay, the world is so beautiful.
分かってる、分かってる、解ってる…分かってるよ！
I understand... I understand!
ごめんね。じれったい
I'm sorry, it's frustrating.
足りない、
It's not enough.
こんなんじゃ誰も愛せないの
I can't love anyone like this.
止めない、止まることは知らないの
I won't stop, I don't know how to stop.
言葉足らず、失くしてしまう物ばかりだ
I'm just lacking words, losing things.
luna say maybe…
Luna say maybe...
降るのは、迷be, rainy
What falls is maze be, rainy.
愛せ、どんな自分でも
Love, even the kind of self you are
navy色に染まるまで
Until you're dyed navy,
時間はかかるかもしれないけど
It might take some time, but
i know, 輝くしかないこと
I know, all I can do is shine.
ハイライト、塗り続けるしかない
Highlight, all I can do is keep painting.
真実はちゃんと、言わなくちゃね
I have to speak the truth properly, don't I?
目に見えるものが、続くっと、ずっと思いたい
What I can see, if it continues, always...
君に、半信半疑な素振りして
Acting half-doubting towards you.
心、空回り、遠回り
Heart, spinning in vain, going in circles.
最低だ、
It's the worst.
もう1回やり直せるのなら
If I could do it over again,
素直になりたい、って願ったジレンマ
I want to be honest, I wished for a dilemma.
このままじゃ何もできない
As it is, I can't do anything alone.
全部、決めるのは自分次第
Everything, what I decide, depends on myself.
初めて背中を見たときに、覚悟を決めたあと
When I saw your back for the first time, I made up my mind.
どこまで行けるのか、届くのか
How far can I go? Can it reach?
分からないよ
I don't know.
臆病がそこに立っている
Cowardice is standing there.
3秒前バックステージ
3 seconds before backstage.
震える背中を君に預けて
Entrusting my trembling back to you.
この運命的出会いはきっと、そう、きっと
This fateful meeting, surely, yes, surely
偶然みたいな、多分、神様のいたずらです。
Like a coincidence, perhaps, it's a prank of God.
どうか、正真正銘のこの思いが君の心にちゃんと届くまで
Please, until these genuine feelings properly reach your heart,
ここで、私、全身全霊で歌うから
Here, I will sing with all my heart.
待ってる、待ってる
I'm waiting, I'm waiting.
だからこの場所を大切にしたいの！
So, I want to cherish this place!
これが正真正銘の私だ！
This is the genuine me!
大丈夫、もう怖くないわ
It's okay, I'm not scared anymore.
たまにつまずくことならあるけど
Even though there are times when I stumble,
一番特等席で君の笑顔が見たいんだ、私だけの特権
I want to see your smile from the best seat, my only privilege.
見えない未来、手探り
Groping in the invisible future,
今日もステージの上で証明して見せるから
I'll prove it to you today on stage.
ここにしかないスクリーン
A screen that only exists here.
really! re@lly!
君にまだ話せてないことばっかりあるんだ、聴いてほしいの
There are still so many things I haven't told you, I want you to listen.
あのね、
Hey...
目覚めの合図
My heart is pounding,
スマホが踊る
It's just the beginning.
そして半分眠った瞳で
With a signal, from the beginning.
見た君で
Waking sign, smartphone dances.
心の震えは A=440Hz(よんよんゼロ)
And, half-asleep eyes, looking at you.
今日のリズムは合言葉で合わせよう
My heart's vibration is A=440Hz.
ドゥルドゥル ドゥルドゥルドゥルドゥ
Let's match today's rhythm with a code word.
一歩前に レガート深呼吸
Duru Duru Duru Duru Du.
会う前には二度の瞬き
One step forward, legato deep breath.
月曜の約束を奏でよう
Before meeting, two blinks.
ねぇ、君と僕の合言葉
Let's play the promise of Monday.
ねえ、君と僕の合図
Hey, our sign, you and me...
もう一歩を踏み出して
Taking one more step forward,
踏み出して 合わせてみよう
stepping out, let's match our steps.
なんでマンデー どうしてサンデー
Why Monday? Why Sunday?
明日へ弾んでいたいの
I want to keep bouncing toward tomorrow.
タクトをシュッ・シュッ 拍手をパン・パン
Baton swish-swish, clapping clap-clap!
ここからはすべてダ・カーポ
From here on, it's all da capo.
日曜日のコーデを飛び越えて
Jumping over Sunday's outfit,
待ってるよ 明日よ 来ないでと願ってしまうほど
I'm waiting for tomorrow, wishing it wouldn't come.
あなたを待ちわびる時間すらも愛おしい
Even the time waiting for you is so lovely.
一歩前に レガート深呼吸
One step forward, legato deep breath.
スタッカートで二度の瞬き
Two blinks in staccato,
月曜の約束を奏でよう
Let's play Monday's promise.
ねえ、君と僕の合図
Hey, our sign, you and me...
奏でよう
Let's play it.
ね、叶うよ
Hey, it will come true.
私たちだけの合図
Our very own special sign.
なんと！最後の曲は、先日リリースの2作目のオリジナル曲「You ＆ 合図」でした！
That's right! The final song was my second original song released recently, "You & Aizu"!
パフパフ！かわいいでしょ、新曲のジャケ写です！
Puff-puff! Isn't it cute? That's the jacket illustration for the new song!
この後、24時…えっと、21日の0時…0時ちょっと噛んじゃいました、21日の0時から配信開始です！
Afterwards, at 24:00... um, 0:00 on the 21st... 0:00, I stumbled a bit, distribution starts at 0:00 on the 21st!
もうね、すごくかわいい振り付けとなっているので、よかったら踊ってみてね！
It has a super cute choreography, so please try dancing to it if you'd like!
さらに、この配信の後MVも、えっと、21時10分からプレミア公開されます！
Furthermore, right after this stream, the MV will premiere at 21:10!
もうこちらの楽曲ですね、あの歌詞もちらっと見えていたから分か、ちょっと気づいてるお前らもね、たくさんコメント欄でさ、ムカムカしていたと思うんですが、
As for this song, you could catch a glimpse of the lyrics, so I'm sure many of you who noticed were feeling frustrated in the comments section,
あの、月曜日だったり、かなでの要素がいっぱい込められている、そういう楽曲となっているので、よかったらね、あの、いっぱい聞いてください！はーい！
but you know, it's a song filled with elements like Mondays and Kanade, so please go ahead and listen to it a lot! Yay!
えっ、と、いうことで皆さん、お待たせのグッズ情報もいってまいりたいと、思います！MVも見てね！えっと、えっと、奏で生誕記念グッズ2026！
Um, so everyone, I'd like to move on to the long-awaited merchandise info! Make sure to watch the MV too! Um, Kanade's 2026 Birthday Commemorative Goods!
パフパフバーン！かわいい！配信開始はこのあと21時20分からだから！
Puff-puff-bam! So cute! The release starts at 21:20 after this, so!
安心しないで最後までちゃんと見ていってね、順番にショールショル、紹介していきます！
Don't relax and make sure to watch until the very end, I'll introduce them one by one!
まずはこちら！てででーん！「奏と待ち合わせ！ポストカードフレーム」！
First is this! Tada! "Kanade & Meeting Date! Postcard Frame"!
今回のキービジュアルを奏と待ち合わせをテーマにgomziママに描いていただきましたので、日常のワンシーンを飾るイメージで作ってみました！かわいいでしょ？
The key visual this time was drawn by gomzi-mama with the theme of meeting up with Kanade, so we made it with the image of decorating a daily scene! Isn't it cute?
2つめは、こちら！
The second one is this!
また奏が落書きしちゃったwTシャツ！
The "Kanade Scribbled Again lol T-shirt"!
奏の落書きTシャツ第2弾！本当に今日は月曜日！
Kanade's scribble T-shirt 2nd edition! Truly today is Monday!
もう月曜日もりだくさんです！ハッピー月曜日！ということで、月曜日Tシャツです！
It's packed with Mondays! Happy Monday! So, it's the Monday T-shirt!
3つめは、こちら！「奏とおそろ！ネックレス」！
The third one is this! "Matching Necklace with Kanade"!
かわいいでしょ？今回キービジュアルの奏とのおそろいの奏モチーフのネックレスです！
Isn't it cute? It's a matching Kanade-motif necklace with the one in the key visual!
確かデビュー日が書かれているはずです、奏の。よかったら、あの、すごいシンプルでスタイリッシュなデザインに落とし込んでみたので、普段アクセサリー付けないよっていう人も是非お手に取って着けてみてください！
I believe my debut date is written on it, Kanade's. If you'd like, well, I incorporated it into a super simple and stylish design, so even those who don't usually wear accessories, please pick it up and try wearing it!
そして4つめ、こちら！「明日は月曜日！w ひょっこりぬいぐるみ」！
And the fourth one, this! "Tomorrow is Monday!w Peek-a-boo Plushie"!
いやもうね、こちらの素敵な、もう素敵なフリップを持った奏のぬいぐるみです！
Man, this is a plushie of Kanade holding a wonderful, wonderful flip sign!
画面モニターとかに引っかけて飾ることができますので、いつでも上から奏が「月曜日だよー」って知らせて出します！いぇーい！
You can hook it onto screen monitors and display it, so Kanade will pop out from above anytime to let you know "It's Monday!" Yay!
最後に、フルセット購入特典パフパフバーン！として数量限定で直筆サイン＆箔押し複製メッセージ入りポストカード、通常版は箔押し複製サイン＆メッセージ入りポストカードとボイスがついてきます！
Lastly, the full-set purchase bonus, puff-puff-bam! As a limited quantity, a postcard with a handwritten sign and foil-stamped duplicate message, the regular version comes with a foil-stamped duplicate signed & messaged postcard and voice!
いよいよですね！
Finally, here it is!
お前らへの感謝とこれからの意気込みをありのまま伝えるフリートークボイスになっています。
It's a free-talk voice conveying my gratitude and future determination to you all.
ボイスはフルセットを購入したら必ずついてくるから安心してね！
The voice comes for sure if you purchase the full set, so rest assured!
以上、グッズ紹介でした！
That was the merchandise introduction!
みんな今日は月曜日だね。
Hey everyone, today is Monday.
そんな月曜日のお前らには……
For you guys on such a Monday...
じゃん！
Ta-da!
犬！今回は犬です！
A dog! This time it's a dog!
今日は月曜日ということで、犬のフリップ今年ね、エイプリルフールネタをこすっていきますよ、わん！
Since today is Monday, I'm going to milk this April Fools' joke this year too, woof!
えーっと、このあと面会にてアンコールライブもやっちゃうよー！
Um, after this, we'll also do an encore live at the visiting room!
このQRコードは何なんだ？アンコールではちょっとお前らのリクエストに応えたりするかも？
What is this QR code? In the encore, maybe I'll answer some of your requests?
ん、このQR、あ、行けない行けない、お前らが読み込んでしまう。
Hmm, this QR, ah, no no, you guys will scan it.
このQRを読み込んだら、えっと、メンバーシップに入れるみたいです。
If you scan this QR, um, it seems you can join the membership.
うん、じゃあ見せないでおこう。見せないでおこう。
Yeah, well, let's not show it. Let's not show it.
え、見せちゃおうかな、どうしようかな。
Eh, should I show it, what should I do?
はい、えーっと……
Yes, um...
それじゃあ、あの、今日は本当にあの、カラオケのライブに見に来てくれてありがとうございました！
Well then, um, thank you so much for coming to see the karaoke live today!
前半生ライブっていうすごいカラオケにおいても挑戦的なライブでして、本当はめちゃくちゃ怖かったんですけど、
It was a challenging live even for karaoke, with the first half live, and I was really scared, but
あの、なんとかかんとか、すごく、ポストエックスだったり、お前らがこう、応援のメッセージを送ってくれたおかげで、すごく、もう緊張もそんなにせず終えられたかなと思います。
um, somehow, thanks to you guys sending support messages on X and stuff, I managed to finish without getting too nervous.
本当に見に来てくれてありがとうございました！
Thank you so much for coming to see me!
それでは、面会アンコールライブでまた会おうね！
Well then, see you again at the visiting room encore live!
ありがとう！またね！チャンネル登録してね！
Thank you! See you! Subscribe to the channel!
見に来てくれて
本当に、本当にありがとう。
Thank you so much for coming to see me.
正直、すごく怖かったけど
お前らが応援してくれたから
To be honest, I was really scared, but since you guys cheered for me,
最後までやり遂げることが
できました。
I was able to pull through to the end.
これからもお前らに胸張れる
推しでいられるように
So that I can remain an oshi you can be proud of from now on,
これからも精一杯がんばります。
ついてきてね！
I'll continue to do my best. Follow me!